<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<blogs>
  <blog>
    <id>1651129232</id>
    <title>How to Brew Coffee at Home</title>
    <author>Ryan Clifford Perez</author>
    <date>Apr/28/2022</date>
    <content>  So you love the coffee from your favorite coffee shop and want to recreate the same quality at home. Many beginners find this intimidating, but I’ve got good news for you: while making specialty-grade espresso-based drinks at home is an expensive investment, manual brewing is much more affordable.&#13;
&#13;
So let’s take a look at how to make your very own brew bar. From filter coffee to immersion, this article will cover everything you need to get started. What’s more, I’ll also be sharing with you some tips for achieving great pour over coffee at home. Because let’s be honest, isn’t the first coffee of the day one of the most important?&#13;
&#13;
(Oh, and if you’re wondering where to buy this equipment, most specialty coffee shops have their own retail shelf. Just ask at your local café – and don’t be afraid to ask the barista for some advice, too.)&#13;
&#13;
COFFEE BEANS&#13;
First of all, of course, beginners need coffee beans! I recommend whole beans rather than ground coffee (more on why in a bit). However, other than that, it’s all down to your personal tastes.&#13;
&#13;
Perhaps you like your coffee floral and fruity. Or maybe you’d prefer something a little nuttier with chocolate notes? Not a problem: just ask the barista at your coffee shop for a recommendation. They probably sell the beans you’ve been drinking there, too!&#13;
&#13;
However, if you want to be a bit more specific in what beans you buyer, consider where your favourite coffees come from and how dark they are roasted. Knowing this will point you in the right direction in the future.&#13;
&#13;
Remember, though, that your coffee’s profile isn’t just about the coffee beans. Your brew method will affect it, as will water temperature, grind size, and more.&#13;
&#13;
Key coffee storage tips:&#13;
The roast date matters! Coffee is a natural product, and so it has a shelf life. This will vary, but a good rule of thumb is to only buy the coffee you’ll drink that week. For a more in-depth take on roast dates and stale coffee, check out this guide.&#13;
Store your coffee in an airtight container at room temperature, and out of direct sunlight. Oh, and never, ever put it in the fridge. It’ll absorb the aromas all the other food in there.</content>
  </blog>
  <blog>
    <id>1651129450</id>
    <title>The Rise of Home Coffee Roasting</title>
    <author>RyanCliffordPerez</author>
    <date>Apr/28/2022</date>
    <content>The specialty coffee scene has spurred an interest in quality coffee for many consumers. It’s never been easier for coffee lovers to experiment with innovative ways of brewing it, and they have access to a wider range of coffees and brewing equipment than ever before. Home coffee roasting is also becoming more popular.&#13;
&#13;
While the average person can purchase a range of different beans and prepare them for consumption from the comfort of their home, some are also starting to take interest in the roasting process, and how it impacts the end result.&#13;
&#13;
Here’s why consumers are increasingly eager to explore home roasting for fun and how this could impact the specialty coffee industry at large.&#13;
&#13;
HOME ROASTING DEFINED&#13;
Before examining why the popularity of home roasting is increasing, the difference between home roasting and micro roasting must be defined. Micro roasting involves purchasing small lots of quality green beans directly from importers or traders and roasting small amounts of it for cafés and businesses. Home roasting is something undertaken recreationally, without the goals of profit, and purely for enjoyment.&#13;
&#13;
Home roasting offers several benefits for coffee enthusiasts. It offers a sense of personal satisfaction and can lead to a deeper appreciation of specialty coffee. As it encourages experimentation, it can lead to a better understanding of how different roast levels impact beans and how different varieties respond to the roasting process. In some circumstances, it could save money in comparison to purchasing already roasted beans.&#13;
&#13;
Depending on the sophistication of the machine used, developing a roast that meets specific goals will help a home roaster develop certain skills which can only be acquired through experience, such as being able to discern a roast’s level according to bean colour, or control the degree of roasting taking place by judging the level of smoke emitted. &#13;
&#13;
As many home roasting machines don’t offer as much control over specific roast variables as commercial machines do, it will likely produce diverse results, and no two batches will be the same – something that could appeal to those looking to explore various qualities of a particular bean.</content>
  </blog>
  <blog>
    <id>1651129498</id>
    <title>A guide to calibrating your espresso recipes</title>
    <author>RyanCliffordPerez</author>
    <date>Apr/28/2022</date>
    <content>In coffee shops across the world, one of the most common challenges baristas face is ensuring that espresso extraction remains consistent throughout each day. Ultimately, creating repeatable recipes for espresso leads to more consistent-tasting coffee, thereby increasing customer satisfaction.&#13;
&#13;
However, in order to extract espresso consistently, baristas must have an in-depth understanding of several extraction variables and how they influence coffee flavour. These include dose, yield, and extraction time.&#13;
&#13;
Shaun Aupiais is a co-founder of the Red Band Academy, a barista training school in South Africa. Shaun is a coach at the academy, which trains young people from South Africa to develop their barista skills, with a focus on future employment opportunities.&#13;
&#13;
In this article, Shaun discusses the different extraction variables which baristas need to understand in order to perfect their espresso recipes.&#13;
&#13;
Learning how to extract great-tasting espresso can be tricky, but there are three variables which you should always take into account.&#13;
&#13;
The first one is the dose. This is the amount of ground coffee which you place in the portafilter to extract as espresso. In most coffee shops around the world, doses typically range between 16g and 22g per double shot of espresso, but this is dependent on the coffee.&#13;
&#13;
Most commercial grinders dose coffee by either time or weight. Generally, gravimetric grinders are preferable to time-based grinders, as they provide more consistent dosing, which can help speed up workflow.&#13;
&#13;
The second variable is extraction time. Typically, time is measured from the moment you insert the portafilter into the machine and begin pushing water through the puck, right up until you reach your target espresso weight. This measures the length of time for which the water is in contact with the coffee grounds.&#13;
&#13;
While total extraction time varies for every coffee you use, it generally ranges between 25 and 30 seconds. If the coffee grounds and water come into contact for too little or too long, it will result in under or overextracted espresso.&#13;
&#13;
Weight (or yield) is the third extraction variable. This is the volume of liquid espresso that you are extracting from the coffee grounds (often called the puck). The average weight of espresso in most coffee shops is between 45ml and 60ml per double espresso – but again, this depends on the coffee you’re using.&#13;
&#13;
So, how can you bring all three variables together to achieve the perfect extraction? Well, there is no magic recipe or quick solution – it takes plenty of practice and persistence.</content>
  </blog>
  <blog>
    <id>1651129581</id>
    <title>What is flash brew coffee?</title>
    <author>RyanCliffordPerez</author>
    <date>Apr/28/2022</date>
    <content>Today, when most people talk about cold coffee, cold brew or iced coffee generally come to mind first. But as far back as the 1960s, people were enjoying an entirely different kind of cold coffee beverage in Japan: Japanese iced coffee, also known as flash brew.&#13;
&#13;
It wasn’t until the late 20th and early 21st century, however, that this beverage started to become popular further afield in the US. Since then, it has played a role in the wider rise of cold coffee.&#13;
&#13;
First things first: with flash brew or Japanese iced coffee, you should start by using a pour over coffee brewer, such as a Hario V60 or Kalita Wave.&#13;
&#13;
The concept is simple. You retain the same ratio of water to coffee, but a proportion of your water weight is frozen as ice. The ice is placed in the server beneath the dripper, while the remaining water is heated to your target brewing temperature and used to brew a kind of pour over coffee concentrate.&#13;
&#13;
This results in a brew that is hot for a brief moment before being quickly chilled, which allows for more nuanced flavours in the final cup. &#13;
&#13;
As with normal filter brewing, following a specific recipe is important, if not more so because of the addition of ice.&#13;
&#13;
To understand the process more closely, I spoke with 2020 UK Brewers Cup Champion Matteo D’Ottavio. He currently works as a barista at WatchHouse in London. &#13;
&#13;
“The way to prepare Japanese iced coffee is to create a concentrate with the first part of the brew, and then balance it with the ice,” he explains. “This way, you get the right amount of solubles without losing the strength.”&#13;
&#13;
He adds that most of the coffee’s soluble compounds are extracted during the first 50% of your brew, while the second half is really there to balance the cup. &#13;
&#13;
Matteo also notes that as well as having a defined recipe, getting your brew ratio right is vital.&#13;
&#13;
“I like to create a beverage with a coffee to water ratio of 1:17,” he says. “Some 65% of the total water should be hot, while the remaining 35% should be ice.”</content>
  </blog>
  <blog>
    <id>1651129637</id>
    <title>Exploring the history of coffee cake</title>
    <author>RyanCliffordPerez</author>
    <date>Apr/28/2022</date>
    <content>When searching the term “coffee cake”, Google pulls up around 2.4 billion results. But the top search results may differ depending on your location.&#13;
&#13;
Around the world, there are several types of coffee cake. Some countries agree the definition encompasses numerous styles of cake which can be consumed alongside coffee, such as streusel crumb cake. However, other regions believe coffee cake should contain some form of coffee – whether brewed, instant, or a concentrate.&#13;
&#13;
To understand more about the origins and variations of coffee cake, I spoke with Frank McGinty, the Director of Marketing for Kaldi’s Coffee Roasting Co. in Missouri, US.&#13;
&#13;
THE HISTORY OF COFFEE CAKE&#13;
Many food blogs describe coffee cake as a cinnamon-infused sponge with a crumbly streusel topping made from butter, sugar, and flour. However, others refer to coffee cake as a coffee-flavoured sponge, often with coffee-flavoured cream and frosting as well.&#13;
&#13;
To understand how these different definitions came about, we must first explore the origins of coffee cake.&#13;
&#13;
According to Food Timeline, the history of coffee cake is not as straightforward as we might think. The modern take on this cake is believed to have evolved from honey cakes that were commonly baked in northern and Central Europe during the 17th century.&#13;
&#13;
At the time, these areas were well known for their sweet breads, so it’s likely that earlier forms of coffee cake had similar textures to bread. They contained yeast, flour, eggs, sugar, nuts, spices, and dried fruits. Streusel crumb toppings were also believed to be common at the time, but recipes soon began to change.&#13;
&#13;
It’s believed that Germany was the first country to pair coffee with cake. By the mid-1600s, coffeehouses were becoming widespread in many German cities – including Hamburg, Dresden, Nuremberg, and Berlin.&#13;
&#13;
By the 19th century, European coffeehouses commonly served sweet breads, small cakes, and cookies with their coffees – often to balance the bitterness of the coffee. As well as Germany, many of these coffeehouses were opening in Nordic countries, as well as in cities such as Vienna, Prague, and Budapest – making coffee cake much more widespread.&#13;
&#13;
CULTURAL AND REGIONAL VARIATIONS&#13;
As coffeehouse culture spread across Europe during the 1800s, many countries began to develop their own unique takes on coffee cake.&#13;
&#13;
In Germany, there were a number of cakes commonly paired with coffee, which were referred to as kaffeekuchen (“coffee cake” in English) or kleine kaffeekuchen (“small coffee cakes”). The crumb-topped streuselkuchen (“streusel cake”) and gugelhopf ring cake (similar to a Bundt cake) were also available in German coffeehouses.&#13;
&#13;
Similarly, the practice of enjoying coffee and cake has been prevalent in Nordic countries for some time. In Sweden, it’s referred to as fika, kaffee in Denmark and Norway, khavi in Finland, and kaffi in Iceland. Depending on the context, these all translate to “coffee” or “to have cake with coffee”, and remain prevalent today.&#13;
&#13;
Traditionally, cinnamon or cardamom buns are consumed with coffee in Scandinavia. These sweet breads are made using yeast and often glazed with sugar syrup. Brown sugar glazed cinnamon and cardamom buns are also common in Denmark, as well as the brunsviger – a brioche-style cake made with yeast and covered in brown sugar caramel. </content>
  </blog>
</blogs>
